# **ALKARIA MANDAL**

IT Analyst & Java Full Stack Developer (6 years 9 months of Exp.)

### **OBJECTIVE**

I am hard-working and goal-driven. Keen interested to learn new things to keep myself updated. Eagerly willing to continue work in Angular Framework, typescript (Front-end) & Spring framework, Spring Boot, Java, Micro Service (Back-end). Acquired with good communication skilland business knowledge. Working in TCS for more than 4 years.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

WORK EXI	
Mar,2021 - Present	Consolidating OSSCore Applications, TCS Technology: Spring Boot/Java/Angular/Spring Security/Spring Data JPA/Rest/OAuthAccess token/GitLab/GitHub/Maven/Docker/Jenkins/Jira Brief Description: Responsible for developing microservices backend API using Java, Spring framework, Spring Boot & RESTful Webservices & also responsible for creating highly interactive and customized SPA for the presentation layer (UI) using Angular, Typescript & Bootstrap. Working on agile scrum methodology & involving daily scrum meeting to update working status.
April,2020 - Feb,2021	Application Migration to Angular & Spring Boot, TCS Technology: Spring Boot/Java/Angular/Spring Security/Spring Data JPA/Rest/OAuthAccess token/GitLab/GitHub/Maven/Docker/Jenkins/Jira Brief Description: Involved in requirements gathering, analysis, design & documentation of the application. Implemented the backend business layers using Java, Spring Boot & RESTful webservices. Followed SDLC best practices such as continuous integration, automated unit test & regression testing.
Nov,2019 - Feb,2020	Jboss Server Migration, TCS

Nov,2019 - Feb,2020	Jboss Server Migration, TCS Technology: Jboss/Jdk8/Tomcat/Docker/Jenkins Brief Description: We had migrated a number of applications from older Tomcat servers without
	impacting functionality. We also upgraded the java environment.
NT 0016	- 1 - 1 1

Nov,2016 - **DAIMLER AG, Wipro** Dec,2018 **Technology**:

**Technology**: JSP/Java/Spring/jquery/AngularJs/SQL

**Brief Description**:

I used to work on UI based web portal development and feature enhancement as well bakend spring applications.

Feb,2016 -	Internship, Wipro
May,2016	Technology: Core Java, Spring, Hibernate,
	JDBC, RDBMS.
	Brief Description:
	I have attended 3 months intership trainee program ogranised by Wipro
	Technologies. Learned lots of new emerging technologies and received the best
	trainee award.

### **SKILLS**

Framework	• Spring Framework
	• Spring Boot
	Spring Security
	Rest API gateway
	• Angular
Tools & IDE	• Spring Tool Suit (STS)
	• Eclipse
J2EE	• Rest
	• SOAP
	• EJB
Build Script	Maven
	• Ant
Repository	• SVN
	• Github
	• Gitlab
Webpage/Js	Angular
	• Typescript
	Bootstrap
	• CSS
Operating System	• Windows
1 0,	• Linux
Language	• Java8
Database	Oracle
	<ul> <li>MySQL</li> </ul>
	•

### **EDUCATION**

Certification	Degree	Discipline	University	Year	%
Post Graduation	MCA	Computer Science	AMU	2016	78.30
Graduation	B.Sc (H)	Chemistry	AMU	2013	70.60
12 <sup>th</sup>	Higher Secondary	Science	WBCHSE	2010	76.67
10 <sup>th</sup>	Secondary	General	WBBSE	2008	78.50

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- ❖ Professional Scrum Master (PSM-I) from Scrum.org in 2019.
- ❖ Full Stack: Angular & Spring Boot from Udemy in 2020.
- ❖ Microservices with spring cloud from Udemy in 2021.
- Spring Boot Microservices with Spring Cloud Beginner to Guru from Udemy in 2021.
- Understanding Typescript from Udemy in 2022

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name	Alkaria Mandal
Date of Birth	09-Jan-1992
Email Id	alkaria.mca40@gmail.com
Phone No.	+91 7417004609
Permanent	Dangapara
Address	L. Dangapara
	Hariharpara
	Murshidabad, West Bengal, India, 742166